Junaitha Begum A. M

9043720227; 9994320227 junaithabegumam@gmail.com Coimbatore, India.

Resume Objective

Professional Chef with experience in multi cuisine 13+ years of North Indian, South Indian, Indo-Chinese & Arabian Cuisines. Capable of managing dining services from 200 to 1000 members i.e 25kg in quantity while supervising and motivating staff to perform the best of their abilities across every service. Thorough understanding of HACCP procedures. Excellent understanding of recipe modification and nutrient composition along with advanced nutrition skills aimed at preparing specialized food items, menu planning, tracking inventory, controlling costs etc.

Education

Jul 2003 to June 2004

Paark Institute of Hotel Management and Catering Technology - *Diploma in Food & Beverage Production*

June 1997 - May 2000

AnnaMalai University , Chidambaram - B. A Sociology

Experience

Jan 2018 - PRESENT

Vijay Elanza 4 Star, Saibaba colony - Chef de cuisine

Key Contribution

- Managing daily kitchen operations with staff members of 10.
- Collaborating with Head Chef for menu redesign and implementing new courses according to guest obligations.
- Overseas food production and preparation, ensuring food safety procedures are 100% adhered to.

Dec 2010 - Dec 2017

Metro Bukit Bintang 3 Star, Kuala Lumpur -Chef de partie

Key Contribution

- Developed food process that increased the economy by 40% simultaneously improved the monthly & yearly turnover to 70%.
- Trained and directed all Commis since 2010, improving kitchen operation flow by 50%, while maintaining 100% employee abilities.

- Redeveloped menu, managed relationships with vendors, negotiating prices of ingredients and equipment that resulted in a 10% savings on budget.
- Prepared meals for lunch and dining services with an average of 200 persons per day

Oct 2006 - Nov 2010

Sangam 3 Star, Thanjavur - Chef de partie

Key Contribution

- Responsible for cuisines courses and making sound decision to help the management achieve it projected sales.
- Mentored and trained four Commis, improving their performance by 20%.

Aug 2005 - Sep 2006

Temple Tower, Thanjavur - Commis

Key Contribution

 Prepared all food items in a 50 - seat South Indian Cuisine restaurant from Breakfast, Lunch to Dinner services, assisting restaurant with maintaining their high standards throughout the year.

March 2001 - Sep 2006

Own Garment Production Company, Thanjavur

Skills

- North Indian cuisine(Bengali, Punjabi, Kashimiri, Lucknow)
- South Indian cuisine(Chettinad, Malabar, Andhra, Mangalorean)
- Indo-Chinese cuisine
- Arabian cuisine
- Knife Skills
- Leadership
- Adaptability
- Collaboration

Others

Gender Female

Language Tamil English(Read,Write) Arabic

(Signature)

Junaitha Begum